Finding Aid for the Georgia Philipps Morgan Bullock papers, 1890-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
Georgia Philipps Morgan Bullock papers
1890-1957
1374
Bullock, Georgia Philipps Morgan, 1878-1957.
18 boxes (9 linear ft.) 23 cartons (23 linear ft.) 23 oversize boxes.
Collection contains correspondence, clippings, speech files, and scrapbooks relating to the legal career of Georgia Phillips Morgan Bullock, attorney and first woman judge of the California Superior Court.
University of California, Los Angeles. Library Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Georgia Bullock, 1954 and 1955.
Gift of Edna Bullock, 1980-1986.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 709513
Biography
Born as Georgia Philipps Morgan in Chicago, 1878; married William Wingfield Bullock in 1899 and had two children; attended Univ. of Southern California (LL.B, 1914), and Southwestern Univ. (LL.D); admitted to CA bar in 1913; deputy district attorney, LA; appointed police judge, 1924-26; judge, LA Municipal Court, 1926-31; judge, CA Superior Court, LA County, 1931-56; retired in 1956; died Aug. 29, 1957.
Scope and Content
Collection contains correspondence, clippings, speech files, and scrapbooks relating to the legal career of Georgia Phillips Morgan Bullock, attorney and first woman judge of the California Superior Court.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Professional and personal files (boxes 1-14)
Calendars (boxes 15-17)
Documents and scrapbooks related to legal career (boxes 18-40)
Awards, printed material, photographs (box 32)
Microfilm reel of testimonial (box 41).
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Bullock, Georgia Philipps Morgan, 1878-1957--Archives.; Women judges--California, Southern--Archival resources.
Genres and Forms of Material
Scrapbooks.
Container List
- Awards
  - Woodbury College honorary degree., 1939 August (Box 32)
- Calendar
  - 1914 (Box 15)
  - 1915 (Box 15)
  - 1920 (Box 15)
  - 1933 (Box 15)
  - 1934 (Box 15)
  - 1935 (Box 15)
  - 1936 (Box 16)
  - 1937 (Box 16)
  - 1938 (Box 16)
  - 1939 (Box 16)
  - 1940 (Box 16)
  - 1941 (Box 17)
  - 1942 (Box 17)
  - 1934 July - 1935 August, In ledger book. (Box 32)
  - Calendar - personal
    - 1940-1941 (Box 16)
    - 1942 (Box 17)
- Correspondence
  - Letter to editor., undated. (Box 14)
  - 1923 (Box 14)
  - Woodbury College., 1931 (Box 14)
  - Bank of America., 1938 (Box 14)
  - University of Southern California., 1941 (Box 14)
  - Christmas cards., 1942 (Box 14)
  - Chavin, Lillian., 1952 (Box 14)
  - Bullock personal letters., 1929 (Box 4)
- Documents
  - Testimonial to GPB ... from the Business & Professional Women's Club of Los Angeles., 1950; 1 volume. (Box 17)
  - Certificate of Appreciation. Presented to GPB by Conference of California Judges., 1952 (Box 18)
  - Certificate of Appreciation. Presented to GPB by Holy Family's Adoptive Parents., 1954 June. (Box 18)
  - California Association of 1952-1953. Secondary School Administrations. Certificate of Contributing Membership. (Box 32)
- Ephemera
  - ca. 1925-1951 (Box 14)
- Microfilm
  - From box 17: Testimonial to Judge Georgia P. Bullock from the business and Professional Women's Club of Los Angeles, 1 reel (positive) (Box 41)
- Personal Files
  - Clippings, biographical material, service citations., Removed from envelope. (Box 32)
  - General private correspondence to 1925. (Box 7)
- Photographs
  - Testimonial dinner for Georgia P. Bullock. Business & Professional Women's Club of Los Angeles., 1950 February 16.; 2 photographs, 1 negative. (Box 32)
- Printed material
  - Legal Informant. vol. 1, no. 8., (1918 February); Bullock, pp. 20-22. (Box 17)
  - Eleusis of Chi Omega., 1956 February; Bullock, portrait between pp. 152-155. (Box 17)
  - The Protector, vol. 5, no. 1, (1953) (Box 32)
  - Phi Delta Delta. vol. 30, no. 1, 1951 November 1 (Box 32)
- Professional Files
  - Psychopathic parole office., [3 folders] (Box 1)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., 1928 (Box 10)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., 1929 (Box 11)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., 1935 (Box 12)
  - National League of the Mothers of America. (Box 13)
  - Campaign forms. (Box 13)
  - Police reports., 1931 (Box 14)
  - Campaign papers., 1936; [3 folders] (Box 2)
  - Committees - Bar Association. (Box 2)
  - Crime., [2 folders] (Box 2)
  - Domestic relations. (Box 2)
  - Insanity. (Box 2)
  - Narcotics. (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous subjects taken from cards. (Box 2)
  - Campaign material., 1924 (Box 3)
  - Clippings. (Box 3)
  - Memos, clippings., ca. 1940, 1946 (Box 5)
  - Traffic. (Box 5)
  - Institutions, hospitals, jails. (Box 5)
  - Fingerprints. (Box 5)
  - Liquor. (Box 5)
  - News releases, background information, etc. (Box 5)
  - Data from Juvenile Hall County Probation Committee. (Box 5)
  - Judge Georgia Bullock - 25th anniversary on bench. (Box 5)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., ca. 1927-1929 (Box 6)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., ca. 1915-1925 (Box 7)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., ca. 1925-1927 (Box 8)
  - Notebook - notes on California law. (Box 9)
  - Georgia Bullock correspondence., 1925 (Box 9)
- Receipts
  - 1928 (Box 14)
- Scrapbooks
  - "Family and photographs.", Includes photographs, ephemera, letters, cards, clippings. (Box 18)
  - "Memory book #1. To 1925.", Includes photographs, ephemera, letters, cards, clippings. (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook, 1937-1938 (Box 20)
  - [Scrapbook - newsclippings], 1938 January - September. (Box 21)
  - Clipping book, no. 1., 1913 July - 1924 July (Box 22)
  - Clipping book, no. 5., 1928 April - 1929 May (Box 23)
  - Campaigns., 1928, 1932, 1938 (Box 24)
  - Clipping book, no. 6., 1929 September - 1931 August (Box 25)
  - Georgia Bullock Judge of Superior Court, Los Angeles County - scrapbook., 1931 August - 1932 March (Box 26)
  - [Scrapbook], 1928 September - 1938 May (Box 27)
  - [Scrapbook - newsclippings], 1935 June - 1938 February (Box 28)
  - [Scrapbook], 1934 May - 1937 July (Box 28)
  - [Scrapbook], 1932 August - 1938 August (Box 29)
  - [Scrapbook], 1940 January - 1941 September (Box 30)
  - Clipping book, no. 3., 1926 January - 1926 December (Box 31)
  - Clippings re women. (Box 32)
  - "Memory book #2 1926 to 1928.", Includes photographs, ephemera, letters, cards, clippings. (Box 33)
  - [Scrapbook #18: newsclippings], 1933-1937 (Box 33)
  - "Clippings, 1928. Campaign for Superior Court - Office No. 3, Primary Election, July, August, September." Scrapbook #10. (Box 34)
  - "Re: Appointment to Superior Court, August 14, 1931." [Scrapbook #14] (Box 34)
  - [Scrapbook #23 - newsclippings], 1943-1944 (Box 35)
  - "Memory book", 1924-1940; [Includes photographs, ephemera, letters, cards, clippings #1.] (Box 36)
  - [Scrapbook #25 - newsclippings], 1945-1946 (Box 37)
  - [Scrapbook #6 - newsclippings], 1916-1937 (Box 37)
  - [Scrapbook #3 - newsclippings], 1912-1914 (Box 38)
  - "Women Lawyers' Association" [#4, mainly letters], 1913-1916 (Box 38)
  - [Scrapbook #7 - mainly letters], 1924-1936 (Box 38)
  - "Clipping book #2", 1912 May to 1925 December (Box 39)
  - "Clipping book #4", 1927 January to 1928 April (Box 40)